# **Dhanapal Jayapandi**

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

11675 Rainwater Dr, Alpharetta, GA 30009

□ (+1) 678-666-0066 | **I** itsdhana@gmail.com | **A** www.amdocs.com | **G** djay93

## Summary\_

Software engineering manager, architect and development expert with 10+ years of professional experience. Extensive track record in designing and implementing elegant and pragmatic solutions for enterprise applications. History of excellence in digital transformation, cloud, data engineering, architecture and technical leadership. Growth mindset kept by seeking new challenges and learning new skills, languages, and tools. Aim to utilize my analytical and technical skills to impact core business strategy and results of a growing higher performance organization.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Amdocs Inc. Atlanta, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Oct. 2011 - Present

- Managed large-scale Enterprise applications in production Mobility CRM (30K users/800K calls per day), Uverse CRM (20K users/400K calls per day), Business eBill (2M users/10B bills per month) and MDE (2M campaigns per day), and led the team of software engineers that implements and maintains these systems.
- · Designed and developed digital bill presentment microservice APIs for an Enterprise Billing portal application.
- Implemented automated deployment pipelines for microservices running as Docker containers using Jenkins, Ansible and Maven.
- Migrated applications from server-side rendering view technologies like JSP/Struts to client-side rendering view technologies, Angular.
- Researched, re-architected and optimized a large billing feed pre-processor that increased the performance of the process by 5x times.
- Developed and maintained a Java/Angular application, MDE, for handling mass data loads, mass campaigns and execution of reports
- Architected and refactored MDE to reduce system coupling. Improved the performance by 500% through multi-threading, asynchronous job processing and reduced the failures.
- Designed and implemented software projects with deliverables of 2M dollars and over each year.
- Participated in the overall design, discussion and proposals regarding the future of the products and solutions offered by Amdocs.
- Was responsible for product deliverables, managing deadlines, deployments, system availability, technology infrastructure and security. Maintained a track record of on-time delivery and high quality.
- Promoted Agile transformation efforts to increase team performance instituted retrospectives, continuous integration, code reviews and automated testing.
- Handled proof of concept efforts to help with pre-sales and also for adopting new DevOps/technology standards.

Amdocs Inc. St. Louis, USA

DEVELOPMENT EXPERT Oct. 2009 - Sep. 2011

- Responsible for the onsite development and maintenance of AT&T Mobility CRM.
- Designed and developed an intuitive and easy-to-use Dispute and Adjustment module that connects to the biller and user authorization levels in AT&T.
- Involved in all project-related decisions at the sales, design, implementation, delivery and ongoing maintenance stages of an Enterprise software project.
- · Oversaw and maintained overall service infrastructure focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Refactored the application code proactively and reduced code complexity to simplify on-going site maintenance.
- Mentored junior software developers providing them with knowledge on best practices and techniques of software development and CRM implementation.

#### **Amdocs Development Ltd**

Limassol, Cyprus

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

July. 2006 - Oct. 2009

- Involved in the development and maintenance of Amdocs CRM implementations AT&T Mobility, AT&T Uverse, Excelcom, Telstra and Isabella.
- Designed and implemented feature enhancements based on customer requirements.
- Upgraded the CRM from v12.5 to v6.0 suite and v6 to v7.5 Amdocs suite for Cingular/AT&T Mobility.
- Implemented Amdocs CRM v7.5 for Isabella, Kazakhstan government to manage e-service tickets.
- Developed proof-of-concept to show business value of Amdocs CRM to DishNET, Telstra and Excelcom.
- · Provided bug fixes, performance fixes, query optimizations and usability improvements.

Amdocs Development Ltd Limassol, Cyprus

SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT Oct. 2004 - Jun. 2006

- Designed, developed and deployed large-scale CRM for TOnline and VFUK.
- Developed a logging framework for TOnline backend applications to logs messages in Eclipse Common Base Event (CBE) format.
- · Analyzed and fixed performance issues and functional defects in existing CRM implementations.
- Provided bug fixes for Amdocs eCare Integration APIs, Orion release.
- Involved in the testing of Orion and Omega releases of Amdocs CRM.

HCL Technologies Chennai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

June. 2003 - Oct. 2004

- Developed DART, Developers Automated Regression Tool, for testing pricing, usage and billing APIs of Convergys Atlys Billing System.
- Enhanced the digital knowledge base of Atlys Billing with latest technologies.

## Key Skills\_\_\_\_

Languages	Java, JavaScript	(ES5/ES6)	), C++, Pyth	on, Ruby, PHP	, Perl, Unix Shells, AWK
-----------	------------------	-----------	--------------	---------------	--------------------------

**Backend** Spring, SpringBoot, Node.js, Express, Rails, Laravel **Frontend** Angular, React.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass

**Databases** Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & Containers Kubernetes, AWS (EKS, Lambda, EC2, IAM, S3), Azure, Serverless Framework

**CI/CD** Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Git, Gitlab, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven

**Systems** Red Hat Linux 5/6/7, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, Weblogic, Apache Tomcat EE, Nginx

**Domain Knowledge** CRM, ETL, BI & Analytics, Order management, Electronic bill payments, Self-service portals, Campaigns

Others Nagios, Vagrant

### Certifications \_\_\_\_

2019	SAFe Agilist,	Scaled Agile	Framework
------	---------------	--------------	-----------

2013 Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI

2008 Sun Certified Java Developer, J2SE 5.0

2006 Sun Certified Web Component Developer, J2EE 1.4

2005 Sun Certified Java Programmer, J2SE 5.0

#### Education\_

#### **College of Engineering (Anna University)**

Guindy, India

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jun. 1999 - May. 2003

- Got Gupta Scholarship which is given to promising students in CSE Dept.